Deception is a fine art.
The Last Vermeer is a drama, history film directed by Dan Friedkin.
A soldier and member of the Dutch resistance investigates stolen art in the wake of the
Second World War, including a Vermeer sold to the Nazis by a flamboyant forger.
Han van Meegeren, played by Guy Pearce.
Joseph Piller, played by Claes Bang.
Minna Holmberg, played by Vicky Krieps.
Esper Dekker, played by Roland Møller.
Alex De Klerks, played by August Diehl.
Bernard Bakker, played by Karl Johnson.
The Last Vermeer is a 2019 American drama film directed by Dan Friedkin from a screenplay by
John Orloff (under the pen name James McGee), Mark Fergus and Hawk Otsby.
It is based on the 2008 book The Man Who Made Vermeers by Jonathan Lopez, and tells the story of Han van Meegeren (played by Guy Pearce), an
art maker who swindles millions of dollars from the Nazis, alongside Dutch Resistance fighter Joseph Piller (Claes Bang).
The film had its worldwide release at the Telluride Film Festival on August 31, 2019, and was theatrically released in
the United States on November 20, 2020, by Sony Pictures Releasing through the TriStar Pictures label.
The film explores themes of amsterdam, netherlands, based
on true story, holland, art, art dealer.
The tone is emotional.